



Personal & Professional Informations

Highly motivated engineer with good level of experience in modern technogies and approaches in IT world in common and DevOps particullary.

My daily intend is to make the world around me better. In my work I strict to automate as much as possible, because I know that human make mistakes.

Contacts

- dovnar.alexander@gmail.com
- Alex Dovnar at LinkedIn (www.linkedin.com/in/aliaksandrdounar)
- Alex Dovnar's personal site (www.dovnaralexander.github.io)
- Alex Dovnar's GitHub (www.github.com/DovnarAlexander)

Working experience

EPAM Systems (www.epam.com)

Apr 2016 - Now

- Has grown from a Junior Systems engineer to the Lead position
- Worked on different projects on different roles as: Team and Technical Lead, Maintainance and Build engineer. Successfully work as a single engineer as well as a part of the team.
- Certified Amazon Web-Services Solution architect (associate level) with 3-year hand-on experience managing 500+ multi-environment compute resources.
- Proven hands-on exprerience with different modern DevOps tools and tecnologies like Ansible\Chef, Terraform, Packer, Python, Jenkins\GitLab Cl\Trevis\GitHub actions.
- Lead and executed the migration of the SaaS Production environment from On-Premise to AWS almost with Zero downtime.
- Designed, lead and supported the development process of the automation code for Infrastructure and Software provisioning with Ansible, Packer and Terraform following Immutable infrastructure approach.
- Designed, created and maintained the fully automated installation process of the Adobe Experience manager CMS (monolith Java Enterprise application for content management).
- Decreased the delivery pipeline for multiple projects minimum on 40% (Jenkins\Java\SonarQube).

Ansible AWS GCP Terraform Packer Git Vagrant Kubernetes EKS KOPS Bash Python Linux Windows Jenkins GitLab CI Travis NewRelic Zabbix Grafana EKL Elasticsearch Prometheus Docker

RUE Beltelecom (www.beltelecom.by)

Mar 2011 - Apr 2016

- Worked as the 1st and 2nd ISP Client support in the call center. Later was promoted to the network on-call engineer responsible for the backbone ISP network support and maintanance.
- Worked following 24x7 support approach to provide high quality service for ISP customers.
- Enterprise clients support (VPN and Ethernet\SHDSL Internet access).
- Initialized and developed multiple automation solution based on scripts for network equipment maintenance.

Huawei Cisco xDSL xPON ISP IPTV VoIP VPN Linux Zabbix

Education

- 2011-2015 > Bachelor's degree: BSUIR (Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics) Informational technologies and management in technical systems
- 2007-2011> College: Belarus State Academy of Communication Technician-programmer in the Networking

Certificates & Courses

- Issued 2019, Valid to 2022> AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate- Link
- Issued 2018, Valid to 2020> Google Cloud Platform Professional Cloud Architect- Link
- Issued 2013> Cisco CCNA